INSTRUCTOR: Hello, everyone,
and welcome to the content
video for how to
update a Github repo.
So this is something
that you'll have
to do multiple times
throughout the semester.
Whenever I add anything or
change anything on the Github
repo, you'll need
to pull it down
to your repository
on your Cloud9 server
so you have all the up-to-date
code throughout the semester.
So how do you do that?
Here's how you do that.
So let's go into
the terminal here.
I'm going to type the command
clear to clear up my console.
OK, and now that I'm in here,
I'm going to do a git status,
which is going to tell
me I'm on the main branch
and everything's up to date.
So here's what
you'll want to do.
Let's say I put out
a message on Slack.
The repo has been updated.
There's code we're going
to cover this week.
Please update your repo.
Here's how you would do that.
The command is
git pull, and that
will pull down all of the
code from the repo back
into your local version.
Now mine says
already up to date,
and that's the
message you'll get
when everything is good to go.
When you're up to date
with the remote repo,
it'll say already up to
date with your local repo.
OK, but oftentimes if you've
changed things, which is great--
if you've changed things
in your local repo,
it'll give you a message, hey--
I forget the exact verbiage,
but basically, you've
updated things
locally or, you know,
there's edits that are
not being tracked locally.
So here's how you handle those.
You could merge them,
but you're never
going to push
anything to my repo,
so you really don't need to
worry about merging anything
because you're just going to
be a consumer of this repo
over and over.
So the command that you want to
just store your changes locally
that you made but still get the
new stuff from the repo, first
do a git stash.
So it'll be git stash
just like that git--
-G-I-T-- stash--
S-T-A-S-H. Hit Enter.
I'm not going to because
I want my changes to be
in sync with the remote repo.
Hit Enter.
Then it'll say a
message like, keeping
track of these local
changes separately.
Then after you do a stash
and a git pull again,
you should get the message
already up to date.
OK, so that's it, that
is how to keep in sync
or keep repulling the code,
latest code from the repo.
That's the end of
the content video.
Thanks for watching.